In this lecture, we're going to focus on Amazon SageMaker Data Wrangler.
So this service focuses on data collection and data pre-processing.
So there are four key steps that you need to follow to enable data processing through
the data Wrangler service.
So the first one is to import the data into data Wrangler from services such as S3, Athena,
and there are 50 plus third-party sources through which you can import data into data
Wrangler.
And you can see all the services that it supports.
You can also do a local upload, maybe an upload CSV file into data Wrangler.
And you can see the screenshot here from data Wrangler.
So here I just imported a data set from the ill-fated ship Titanic.
And you can see in this data set, you have the passenger class, survived one for
survived and zero for wooden survive, the names of all the passengers, age, ticket,
fare and so on.
So once you have imported this data, the next is to understand the data quality and then generate
data insights.
And this is also called as exploratory data analysis.
And you should remember this from the exam perspective, there's a very good chance that
they might ask about which AWS service is used for exploratory data analysis.
Now let's try and understand better what we do as part of this step.
So now you can see from the screenshot, once we have imported that Titanic data, you can
have a table summary view here and here are all the data points.
And it shows you a summary view.
So it will show you the passenger class, it's about 1309, survived, we have about 1309 records.
But if you look at the age, you have only one, zero, four, six.
So you can imagine that there are some data points that are missing.
So that's how you can understand the data quality.
Then the next is exploratory data analysis.
And here you can see, you can generate a histogram and there are other chart types.
You can use bar chart, pie chart and so on.
And here we have on the X axis, we have the six and then we have the color by survive.
So for males and females, what was the percentage that survived?
So this is the percentage for males that survived and this is the percentage for females.
So you can use different chart types to analyze the data, also sometimes called as exploratory
data analysis.
So once you have understood the data quality and generated data insights, the third step
is to transform data more efficiently and analyze.
So here you might want to drop some columns, handle outliers and let's say, so we're trying
to predict what kind of passenger survived.
Maybe you don't need a column with address of the people as that might not be a factor
in whether they survive or not.
So what you can do is you can use either custom transformation or some prebuilt transformation
to drop the column or handle outliers, handle missing data.
So those are the capabilities that are provided by data handler.
So you can see here, so you can do the transformation either through prebuilt capabilities
or custom transformations.
So once you have transformed the data, then you can export the data either to S3 or SageMaker
feature store and we'll discuss about SageMaker feature store next or you can also use SageMaker
pipelines.
So hopefully the Amazon SageMaker data wrangler capabilities are clear to you.
I'll see you in the next lecture, thank you.